<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Stuff</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:40:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is this thing dead yet?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2016-12-19-is-this-thing-dead-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2016-12-19-is-this-thing-dead-yet/</guid>
      <description>I did it, I finished my masters in Informatics. After five and a half years I finally don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry any more about exams and tasks for the university. A relieving feeling.
Retrospective Looking back at the time in the university (University of Applied Sciences Berlin) I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I took the challenge of starting to study. As I don&amp;rsquo;t have the normally mandatory &amp;ldquo;Abitur&amp;rdquo; I was only able to study because auf my apprenticeship and work experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kick Ass - Comic vs. Movie</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2012-10-03-kick-ass-comic-vs-movie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 22:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2012-10-03-kick-ass-comic-vs-movie/</guid>
      <description>Whoohoo I loved Kick Ass The movie, but now that I&amp;rsquo;ve read the underlaying comic, I think a little bit different about the movie. At least in the story there are major changes
The movie is, for it self, very entertaining. The cast of the movie was well done and consistent. I think the actors matched the characters and especialy that Hit Girl was a good cast. The soundtrackis entertaining and the track &amp;ldquo;stand up&amp;rdquo; from &amp;ldquo;the prodigy&amp;rdquo; is at least for me inseparably associated with this movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Desert Spear - Peter v. Brett</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2012-02-24-the-desert-spear-peter-v-brett/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 23:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2012-02-24-the-desert-spear-peter-v-brett/</guid>
      <description>Dang! that was enthralling. I just read Peter V. Brett&amp;rsquo;s second novel &amp;ldquo;Desert spear&amp;rdquo; from the demon cycle. I&amp;rsquo;m still a little bit agitated. I&amp;rsquo;ve read the first book a while ago and found it very good. In my opinion the second book is even better than the first one. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t refrain from reading it for about 7 hours today&amp;hellip;
I realy like how the author Peter V. Brett wove the plots with the different characters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>