<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on Stuff</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on Stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 21:05:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir on Raspberry Pi 2 (using Windows)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2015-12-20-elixir-on-raspberry-pi-2-using-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 21:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2015-12-20-elixir-on-raspberry-pi-2-using-windows/</guid>
      <description>Goal Deploy an example Elixir application with the Nerves-Project to a Raspberry Pi 2, using an Ubuntu guest in VMware Player on a Windows host.
Synopsis We are using the Nerves-project, buildroot and Ubuntu in a virtual machine to create a SD-Image, which contains the default application, blinky.
Motivation After seeing this talk from Garth Hitchens on Embedded Elixir in Action I wanted to try the Nerves project to deploy an Elixir application to my Raspberry Pi 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing data with Gnuplot</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2012-02-17-visualizing-data-with-gnuplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 20:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2012-02-17-visualizing-data-with-gnuplot/</guid>
      <description>On my pursuade for a tool to visualize simple list values I found gnuplot:
from Wikipedia:
 gnuplot is a command-line program that can generate two- and three-dimensional plots of functions, data, and data fits.
 I will focus on the capabilities of gnuplot on two-dimensional plots and in special howto visualize data without a corresponding second data value. But first here is the idea why I needed such a tool:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install HandBrake on Ubuntu 11.10</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2011-11-03-how-to-install-handbrake-on-ubuntu-11-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 09:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2011-11-03-how-to-install-handbrake-on-ubuntu-11-10/</guid>
      <description>If not already happened: Install the synaptic package manager (search for synaptic in the Ubuntu software center)
Download this package according to your architecture. If you are not sure which architecture you need, try amd64 or i386. This are the two most used architectures.
Install the package by double clicking.
Open a terminal and execute sudo add-apt-repository ppa:stebbins/handbrake-releases
Open synaptics package manager, go to preferences / package sources / other software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>