<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Howto on Stuff</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Howto on Stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 21:45:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Wifi on Ubuntu 12.04 Server via command line (yeah, finally some technical stuff )</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2012-10-22-setting-up-wifi-on-ubuntu-12-04-server-via-command-line-yeah-finally-some-technical-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 21:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2012-10-22-setting-up-wifi-on-ubuntu-12-04-server-via-command-line-yeah-finally-some-technical-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Problem: Setting up a wireless adapter on Ubuntu server 12.04 LTS via CLI isn&amp;rsquo;t THAT easy. Plug&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;Play doesn&amp;rsquo;t simply work. Good thing there is Google. And a lot of helpful sites.
Target: Insert the stick (or boot with it) and connect automaticly to the preferred network
This is not a tutorial. And it&amp;rsquo;s realy not for the uninitiated. It&amp;rsquo;s more like a short reminder for me, or people who have a basic idea what&amp;rsquo;s happening here&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing data with Gnuplot</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2012-02-17-visualizing-data-with-gnuplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2012 20:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2012-02-17-visualizing-data-with-gnuplot/</guid>
      <description>On my pursuade for a tool to visualize simple list values I found gnuplot:
from Wikipedia:
 gnuplot is a command-line program that can generate two- and three-dimensional plots of functions, data, and data fits.
 I will focus on the capabilities of gnuplot on two-dimensional plots and in special howto visualize data without a corresponding second data value. But first here is the idea why I needed such a tool:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install HandBrake on Ubuntu 11.10</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2011-11-03-how-to-install-handbrake-on-ubuntu-11-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2011 09:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2011-11-03-how-to-install-handbrake-on-ubuntu-11-10/</guid>
      <description>If not already happened: Install the synaptic package manager (search for synaptic in the Ubuntu software center)
Download this package according to your architecture. If you are not sure which architecture you need, try amd64 or i386. This are the two most used architectures.
Install the package by double clicking.
Open a terminal and execute sudo add-apt-repository ppa:stebbins/handbrake-releases
Open synaptics package manager, go to preferences / package sources / other software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>