<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Stuff</title>
    <link>http://example.org/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 12:00:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom.io now works on German keyboards!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2015-12-19-atom-io-now-works-on-german-keyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 12:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2015-12-19-atom-io-now-works-on-german-keyboards/</guid>
      <description>Summary: If you have problems with non us-keyboards and the editor Atom.io install this package: keyboard-localization
Shortly longer: Ok, I blogged about my problems with Atom.io before (and before) and the underlying issues aren&amp;rsquo;t fixed in the chromium parts of Atom.io. Yet there were workarounds: For example I created my own keybinding file, which fixed my most important issue the missing &amp;ldquo;@&amp;rdquo; sign (who is using that, anyway?). Now I needed an working &amp;ldquo;\&amp;rdquo; in my elixir code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YNAB - One year review</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2015-04-09-ynab-one-year-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 15:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2015-04-09-ynab-one-year-review/</guid>
      <description>Tl;dr: YNAB4 is awesome and you should give it a try. I managed my finances!
How the time flies by! A year ago I installed You Need A Budget 4 as trial on my system. Since then I used the software (or the Android version) everyday. After the trial period I asked the ynab.com for the free student version of their software. After the license key arrived everything worked fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Need A Budget - Free students licence</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/2014-06-04-you-need-a-budget-free-students-licence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 21:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/2014-06-04-you-need-a-budget-free-students-licence/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the software You Need A Budget for my budgeting purposes. I was evaluating the software after I realized that my Excel solution is not feasible (read: to complicated).
I installed the 30 days trial version until it expired. After that I uninstalled it and used the Steam demo version. So I had double the evaluation time. And evaluate I did. After that time I was this close to actually purchase YNAB 4 via Steam.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>